[
    {
        "question": "In what city is Gonzaga University located?",
        "answer": "Spokane, Washington"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to the world`s largest naval base?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Greenland is a dependency of what European country?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "What winter sport`s Hall of Fame is located in Ishpeming, Michigan?",
        "answer": "Skiing"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is named after a King of England?",
        "answer": "Georgia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only major port city in Alabama?",
        "answer": "Mobile"
    },
    {
        "question": "The coast of what National Seashore is known as the `Graveyard of the Atlantic`?",
        "answer": "Cape Hatteras National Seashore"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lake of the Ozarks is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "Missouri"
    },
    {
        "question": "What line of Latitude lies at 23 degrees and 27 minutes north of the equator?",
        "answer": "Tropic of Cancer"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the tallest mountain in the world that is not part of the Himalayas or the Andes?",
        "answer": "K2"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many US state capital city`s names begin with the letter `S`?",
        "answer": "6"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US state is Puget Sound located?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation`s legislative body is named The Great Khural?",
        "answer": "Mongolia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation`s legislative body is named The Kuvendi?",
        "answer": "Albania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country measures its `gross national happiness`?",
        "answer": "Bhutan -- The index seeks to measure the happiness and general wellbeing of its population. Metrics include psychological well-being, good governance, and community vitality."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the state bird for the U.S. state Missouri?",
        "answer": "Eastern bluebird -- Missouri was one of the first states to designate an official state bird in 1927. It is also the state bird of New York."
    },
    {
        "question": "What notorious pirate has a U.S. national historic park named after him?",
        "answer": "Jean Lafitte -- The British asked for his help, but Lafitte warned U.S. authorities and offered to help defend New Orleans in exchange for pardons for his men."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. Midwestern town is known as `America`s Little Switzerland`?",
        "answer": "New Glarus, Wisconsin -- It doesn`t have mountains, but it makes up for it with high-quality beer, Alpine cuisine, and a charming main street of chalet-style buildings."
    },
    {
        "question": "The unfinished cathedral Basilica of San Petronio is located where?",
        "answer": "Bologna, Italy -- Had it been finished, it would have been bigger than St. Peter`s Basilica, which is probably why Pope Pius IV blocked its construction."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the world`s top-ten highest peaks is not in the Himalayas?",
        "answer": "K2 -- Also known as Mount Godwin Austen, Qogir Feng, Dapsang, and Chogori, it is in the Karakoram Range on the border of China and Pakistan."
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Temujin change his name to?",
        "answer": "Genghis Khan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was Genghis Khan`s birth name?",
        "answer": "Temujin"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Western Samoa?",
        "answer": "Apia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Apia is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Samoa"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the Tonga?",
        "answer": "Nuku`alofa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nuku`alofa is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Tonga"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the official state fruit of New Hampshire?",
        "answer": "Pumpkin"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s largest living tree canopy, the size of three soccer fields?",
        "answer": "India -- A 550-year-old ficus benghalensis tree there, known as Thimmamma Marrimanu, has combined crowns that span 5.41 acres."
    },
    {
        "question": "What island changes hands between France and Spain every six months?",
        "answer": "Pheasant Island -- The two-acre island lies in the Bidasoa River between France and Spain."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s largest Roman aqueduct that is still in use?",
        "answer": "Spain -- The Segovia aqueduct, built in the first century A.D., carries water from the Fuente Fr\u00eda River to the city of Segovia."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Camp David`s official name?",
        "answer": "Naval Support Facility Thurmont -- President Eisenhower named it Camp David after his grandson, David."
    },
    {
        "question": "`The Blue House` is the official residence of the leader of what country?",
        "answer": "South Korea -- Originally known as `Gyeongmudae`, the name was changed in 1960 to `Cheong Wa Dae`, meaning blue house."
    },
    {
        "question": "Cape Hatteras National Seashore is located on which coast?",
        "answer": "Atlantic coast"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lake Champlain lies on the border between Vermont and which other US state?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US state is Shenandoah National Park located?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to both the highest and lowest points in the contiguous 48 US states?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "The islands called Islas Malvinas by the Argentinians are referred to by what name by the British?",
        "answer": "The Falklands"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state`s license plates sport the slogan `First in Flight`?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Benelux is a union in Western Europe that is comprised of what three neighboring countries?",
        "answer": "Belgium, The Netherlands, and Luxembourg"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vienna and Belgrade lie on the banks of which river?",
        "answer": "The Danube"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the largest island of the Inner Hebrides?",
        "answer": "Skye"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country would you find the state of Tabasco?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is home to the world`s most rapidly-constructed skyscraper?",
        "answer": "China -- Broad Sustainable Building company built a 57-story building called Mini Sky City in 19 days using prefab components."
    },
    {
        "question": "What color are gondolas required to be painted in Venice?",
        "answer": "Black -- A 17th century doge`s decree dictated that all gondolas must be painted with six coats of black paint."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which mountain range separates Spain from France?",
        "answer": "Pyrenees"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is home to the original Highland Games?",
        "answer": "Scotland"
    },
    {
        "question": "The path known as `Silk Road` stretched for 4,000 miles from China to where?",
        "answer": "Rome"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many states does the Appalachian Trail traverse?",
        "answer": "14"
    },
    {
        "question": "What U.S. State was the first to recognize Christmas as an offical holiday?",
        "answer": "Alabama"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what part of the former Soviet Union did the Chernobyl nuclear disaster occur?",
        "answer": "Ukraine"
    }
]